<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Raghav Chawla</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A year at intel</title>
      <link>/post/year-at-intel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/year-at-intel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined Intel in June 2018 and it feels just like yesterday. This journey has been full of technical learning and professional development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working in the Physical Design team of the Image Processing Unit here, working on meeting partition constraints of power, frequency, and area. This involves working upon new algorithms for improving the quality and speed of convergence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work under some amazing mentors who motivate me to challenge myself time and again. My colleagues share my enthusiasm and are always there to help me with my ideas. Working till late in the evening and brainstorming sessions are the best parts of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being my first company, Intel has helped me to get the gist of what is actually done in various teams across the Industry, a perspective far from what I (we) had (have) in college about the Industry. While this may not be the best place to be if you want to do Academic/ Industrial research, Intel taught me a lot about how the Industry works and how various teams collaborate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going on team outings is definitely one of the major events we look up to. Sharing the common love for food, we have been to almost every buffet in Bangalore during team lunches every fortnight. The recent potluck lunches have certainly played their part in bringing us together as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, at Intel, I find a culture conducive for growth and learning. Whether I wish to work from home or leave the office early, there are no questions asked as long as I do justice with the work. My mentors have always encouraged me to think of new ideas and work on them. The schedule becomes hectic sporadically, but we have always worked as a team in meeting deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
